{
  "response": [
    {
      "question": "Jenkins was developed for",
      "option1": "Continuous Integration",
      "option2": "Continuous Monitoring",
      "option3": "Continuous Delivery",
      "option4": "Continuous Deployment",
      "answer": "Continuous Integration"
    },
    {
      "question": "Jenkins can be integrated with",
      "option1": "Git",
      "option2": "Maven",
      "option3": "All of these",
      "option4": "Perforce",
      "answer": "All of these"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the below command is used to install jenkins?",
      "option1": "java-jar jenkins.war" ,
      "option2": "java-jar jenkins.jar",
      "option3": "java-war jenkins.war",
      "option4": "java-war jenkins.jar",
      "answer": "java-jar jenkins.war"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which scripting language is used in Jenkins?",
      "option1":  "Groovy",
      "option2":  "Bash",
      "option3":  "Perl",
      "option4": "Python",
      "answer": "Groovy"
    },
    {
      "question": "Jenkins can only written in",
      "option1":  "C++",
      "option2": ".Net",
      "option3":"Java",
      "option4":  "none",
      "answer": "Java"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two components jenkins is mainly integrated with",
      "option1":  "Version Control System like Git,SVN",
      "option2":  "Build Tools like Apache Maven",
      "option3":  "both of the above",
      "option4": "none of the above",
      "answer": "both of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can u setup jenkins jobs",
      "option1": "Select new item from the menu",
      "option2":"After that enter the name of the job and select free style job",
      "option3": "Than click OK to create a new job in jenins",
      "option4":"All",
      "answer": "All"
    },
    {
      "question": "Jenkins is a",
      "option1":  "Open Source Automation Server",
      "option2":  "Open Source Code",
      "option3":  "both of the above",
      "option4": "none of the above",
      "answer": "Open Source Automation Server"
    },
    {
      "question": "what are the possible actions you will perform to fix a broken build in Jenkins",
      "option1": "check console output for missing file changes",
      "option2":"Clean and Update Local Workspace",
      "option3": "Check job configuration",
      "option4":"All of the above",
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "which one of the following is functionality of continuous integration?",
      "option1":  "repository management",
      "option2":  "code versioning",
      "option3":  "code quality metrics",
      "option4": "configuration management",
      "answer":  "code versioning"
    },
    {
      "question": "What Jenkins cannot do?",
      "option1":  "Generate test reports",
      "option2":  "Integrate with many different Version Control Systems",
      "option3":  "Push to various artifact repositories",
      "option4": "Enviromental provisioning",
      "answer":  "Enviromental provisioning"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the scripts are used by jenkins to execute builds?",
      "option1":  "Python",
      "option2": "Ruby",
      "option3":"Groovy",
      "option4":  "All",
      "answer": "All"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Jenkins ?",
      "option1":  "Continuous integration tool",
      "option2":  "Continuous delivery tool",
      "option3":  "Both of the above",
      "option4": "None of the above",
      "answer":  "Both of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not support by CI ?",
     "option1":  "Automated build process",
      "option2":  "Automated deployment to production",
      "option3":  "Automated unit test",
      "option4": "Automated code quality checks",
      "answer":  "Automated deployment to production"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of below is not a dependency management tool?",
     "option1":  "Ant",
      "option2":  "Maven",
      "option3":  "Gradle",
      "option4": "Jenkins",
      "answer":  "Jenkins"
    },
    {
      "question": "Can we run Junits as a part of Jenkins job?",
     "option1":  "True",
      "option2":  "False",
      "option3":  "May be",
      "option4": "none of the above",
      "answer":  "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which plugin allows jenkins to create pipelines?",
     "option1":  "JenkinsFile",
      "option2":  "Job DSL",
      "option3":  "All of these",
      "option4": "Pipeline",
      "answer":  "Pipeline"
    }
  ]
}